# Ramón Everardo Hernández Hernández

Bachelor in Communications and Electronics Engineering Student

+52 7831402477 in in/ramonevehdez

ramstric@gmail.com
github.com/Ramstric

Mexico City, CDMXramstric.github.io

# PROFILE TECH STACK

Suitable engineering student with a commitment to scientific research and technological advancement in Mexico, I have 5 years of experience in software development through multiple personal projects, applying modern tech tools used in the current work field.

Skills

Python

C# Lua

C++

JavaScript

### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor in Communications and Electronics Engineering

**ESIME Campus Zacatenco** 

## 2020 - Present

Mexico City, Mexico

**Relevant Courses:** Local Area Networks, Software Engineering, Engineering Quality, Numerical Analysis, Data structures & Algorithms and Computers architecture.

#### **Databases**

MySQL

#### **Cloud platforms**

Azure

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Research assistant

#### **Computing Research Center**

Nov 2023 - Present

- Mexico City, Mexico
- ullet Implementation of numerical methods for simulation modeling in **Python**
- Numerical solution programming with NumPy
- Interpretation of results and plots using **matplotlib**
- Data analysis and manipulation using pandas
- Use of **GitHub** repositories and use of the **Git** version control system
- General approach to **simulation** using partial differential equations (**PDEs**)

#### **Software**

MatLab

Code Composer Studio

Cisco Packet Tracer

OrCAD Capture CIS

NI Multisim

# Project - Embedded Programming with RP2040

### **ESIME Campus Zacatenco**

may 2023 - Jul 2023

- Mexico City, Mexico
- Development of an **embedded system** in **MicroPython** and **C** languages
- Use of multithreading for the execution of two processes on the RP2040 microcontroller
- Proper integration of multiple electronic components according to manufacturers datasheets
- Writing of systematic documentation and schematization of electronic circuits

# LANGUAGES

- Spanish [Native]
- **English** [C1 Advanced]

### Project - Habilis VR Glove

#### **CETMAR No. 20**

**m** Oct 2019 - Jun 2020

- Veracruz, Mexico
- Interpretation and manipulation of analog measurements via **serial communication** using an **ATmega328** microcontroller
- · Connection bridge between Arduino and Unity 3D via .NET
- Writing of **systematic documentation** for the project
- Participation in technology project events as an exhibitor